Castle-Bache Collection 1683-1922 Mss.Film.1506
American Philosophical Society
Castle-Bache Collection
1683-1922
Mss.Film.1506
American Philosophical Society
9.0 Reel(s)
A leading Jeffersonian journalist, Benjamin Franklin Bache was the eldest son of Richard and Sarah (Franklin) Bache, and grandson of Benjamin Franklin. Educated in France and Switzerland, Bache returned to the United States with his grandfather in 1785 and by 1790, had established himself as editor of the Aurora, a newspaper that became one of the most important voices for radical Republicanism in early national Philadelphia. Bache died in the yellow fever epidemic of 1798. His son Franklin Bache became a noted physician and chemist, teaching at the Franklin Institute (1826-1832), the Philadelphia College of Pharmacy and Science (1831-1841), and at Jefferson Medical College. The Castle-Bache Collection contains a diverse assemblage of both personal and professional correspondence relating to the grandson of Benjamin Franklin, Benjamin Franklin Bache, with interesting material relating to Bache's son, Franklin, and later generations of the Bache family. The collection also includes genealogical materials on the Franklins, Baches, Markoes, and cognate families, as well as a selection of miscellaneous printed materials.
Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798
Castle family
Reel 1-9
Early American History Note
This is a microfilm of an early American collection that may be of interest to researchers at the APS and may complement an original manuscript collection at the APS.
Related Archival Materials note
The APS houses a small collection of the Papers of Benjamin Franklin Bache and a large number of collections relating to Benjamin Franklin. The Library also has a diary kept by Bache when he was a young boy at school in Switzerland (B B122d).
The APS has a partial run of Bache's newspaper, the Aurora.
Existence and Location of Originals note
The Castle-Bache Collection was microfilmed in 1990 and the originals returned to the family. The collection was owned by the great-great-great grandchildren of Benjamin Franklin Bache and Margaret Hartman (Markoe) Bache. They had been arranged by the Castle family, who made typescripts of many of the most important items. The Castle's numbering system for the collection has been recorded on the upper right have corner of each document folder.
Scope and Contents note
The Castle-Bache Collection contains personal papers, correspondence, notes, financial records, genealogical research, and printed materials that have descended through the Bache family. At the core of the collection is a diverse assemblage of both personal and professional correspondence relating to the grandson of Benjamin Franklin, Benjamin Franklin Bache, with interesting material relating to Bache's son, Franklin.
The materials relating to Benjamin Franklin Bache include everything from schoolboy essays and diaries, to correspondence with his grandfather, parents, and his fiancé Margaret Hartman Markoe. The collection also includes materials relating to the estate of Francis Markoe in St. Croix, to which Margaret and her children were heirs. His professional correspondence includes letters from a number of noteworthy political figures, including Thomas Jefferson, Thomas Paine, and James Monroe.
Franklin Bache is well represented by correspondence and records of his professional accomplishments and the honors he received. Lesser quantities of materials document later Bache generations, including Alexander Dallas Bache (1806-1867), Thomas Hewson Bache (1826-1890), Charles Meigs Bache (1829-1890), Albert Dabadie Bache (1832-1895), and Franklin Bache (1869-1946).
The genealogical materials relate to the Bache, Dabadie, Duane, Elliccott, Franklin, Hartman, Markoe, Read, and Trigg families.
Biographical/Historical note
A leading Jeffersonian journalist and editor of the Aurora, one of the most important newspapers in early national Philadelphia, Benjamin Franklin Bache was born in 1769, the eldest son of Richard and Sarah (Franklin) Bache, and grandson of Benjamin Franklin. In the fall of 1776, the eight year old Bache accompanied his grandfather and cousin William Temple Franklin to Paris. Provided with a excellent education there and in Geneva, he was also introduced to the printing trade through the Parisian printing house of Didot.
Returning to Philadelphia in 1785, Bache finished his education at the University of Pennsylvania and in 1790, he founded the Aurora, which quickly earned a reputation as a leading Republican organ, and just as quickly earned the wrath of Federalists for his unrelenting attacks on the Washington and Adams administrations.
Bache married Margaret Hartman Markoe in 1791, the eldest daughter of Francis and Elizabeth Markoe, wealthy planters from the Caribbean island of St. Croix. The couple had four children before Bache died in September 1798, a victim of the yellow fever epidemic. Margaret Bache continued to operate the Aurora for several months before handing operation of the newspaper to William Duane, an Irish-immigrant and Republican radical whom she eventually married.
Franklin Bache, a physician, teacher, and chemist, was the eldest son of Benjamin Franklin Bache and Margaret Hartman Bache. Educated at the University of Pennsylvania, he received his MD in 1814 after serving as a military surgeon during the War of 1812. Bache published numerous works on chemistry and taught at the Franklin Institute (1826-1832), the Philadelphia College of Pharmacy and Science (1831-1841), and at Jefferson Medical College (1841-1864). He received honors internationally for his work, and served as secretary, vice-president, and president of the American Philosophical Society. He married Aglae Dabadie in 1818, with whom he had eight children.
Bache family; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867; Bache, Albert Dabadie, 1832-1895; Bache, Charles Meigs, 1829-1890; Bache, Franklin, 1792-1864; Bache, Franklin, 1869-1946; Bache, Richard, 1737-1811; Bache, Sarah Franklin, 1743-1808; Bache, Thomas Hewson, 1826-1890; Dabadie family; Darlington, William, 1782-1863; Duane family; Duane, Margaret Hartman Markoe Bache; Duane, William, 1760-1835; Fox, George, 1759-1828; Franklin family; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790; Franklin, William Temple, 1760-1823; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Markoe family; Markoe, Francis; Markoe, Peter, 1752?-1792; Monroe, James, 1758-1831; Paine, Thomas, 1737-1809; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860; Tone, Matilda; Aurora (Philadelphia, Pa.); Microfilm; Microfilm Collection; Moral philosophy; Newspapers--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia; Philadelphia (Pa.)--Politics and government--1783-1815; Physicians--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Medical care; United States--Politics and government--1783-1815
- Series I. Correspondence, 1683-1922; 3 lin. feet
  - Copies of seven deeds for land in Philadelphia County, 1683 Sept. 9-1754 Oct. 10 (Reel 1)
  - To Theodore Bache, 1766? June 29; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Lydia (Reel 1)
  - To Richard Bache, 1766? July 5; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Martha (Reel 1)
  - To Richard Bache, 1766? July 6; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Lydia (Reel 1)
  - Copies of letters made by Thomas Hewson Bache, 1774 Feb. 2-1798 Nov. 29; Franklin, Benjamin and William Franklin (Reel 1)
  - Mathematics notebook, 1776; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 1)
  - To Richard Bache, 1780?; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - Papers relating to the administration and settlement of the estate of Francis and Elizabeth Markoe in St. Croix, 1776-1821 (Reel 1)
  - To William Howe, 1778 Mar. 6; Orig. and typescript; Fergusson, Henry Hugh (Reel 1)
  - Passport for William Temple Franklin, 1778 Dec. 20; France (Reel 1)
  - To [David and Thomas Fitzhugh]?, 1781 Apr. 23; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1781 Aug. 16; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Also including Gabriel Louis de Marignac to Benjamin Franklin
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1781 Sept. 29; Orig. and typescript; Johonnot, Samuel Cooper (Reel 1)
    Also Benjamin Franklin Bache to Benjamin Franklin and Gabriel Louis de Marignac to Benjamin Franklin
  - To William Temple Franklin, 1781?; Fitzhugh, David and Thomas (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1782 Feb. 2; Bache, Sarah (Reel 1)
  - Journal, 1782 Aug. 1-Dec. 5; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - Journal, 1782 Aug. 1-1785 Sept. 14; Typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - Journal, 1782 Aug. 1-1785 Sept. 14; Transcript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
    Transcript in English by Margaret Hartman Bache
  - Journal, 1782 Aug. 1-1785 Sept. 14; Translation; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - Bank draft on Benjamin Franklin's account, 1782 Sept. 18; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - Bank draft on Benjamin Franklin's account, 1782 Sept. 20; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1782 Oct. 1; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1782 Oct. 1; Bache, William (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1782 Oct. 15; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - Illustrations of coats of arms, 1782-1783; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - Journal, 1783 Jan. 1-Apr. 30; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1783 Feb. 25; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1783 March 30; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1783 May 30; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1783 June 20; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1783 July 2; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Richard Bache, 1783 Dec. 3; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
    Also includes Benjamin Franklin Bache to Sarah Bache
  - Journal, 1784 Jan. 1-July 15; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - To Wilhelm and Jan Willink, Jan Nicolass and Jacob van Staphorst, de la Land and Fringe, 1784 Feb. 12; Orig. and typescript; Morris, Robert (Reel 1)
  - To Sarah Bache, 1784 June 17; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 1)
  - Journal, 1784 July 17-Dec. 31; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Explication des machines necessaries pour la fonte des caracteres, 1784 Nov.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Depences de l'année 1784 a Passy, Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Journal, 1785 Jan. 2-June 30; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Varietés, 1785 Mar.-Apr..; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Journal, 1785 July 12-Sept. 14; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Melange, 1786 May-Nov.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Moral Philosophy, vol. 1, 1786; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Moral philosophy, vol. 2, 1786; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1787 July 31; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1787 Aug. 1; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1787 Aug. 8; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To William Temple Franklin, 1788 Sept. 11; Bache, William (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1798 May 7; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1789 Sept. 21; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1789 Nov. 22; Orig. and typescript; Coxe, Mary (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1789 Dec. 6; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - Notebook of resolutions and plan for self-improvement, 1789; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin, 1789?; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 Jan. 28; ADf; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 Jan. 28; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 Feb. 4; ADf; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 Feb. 4; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 March 20; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 March 22; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 March 27; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 Apr. 1; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 May 2; Typescript only; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 May 2; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 June 10; Orig. and typescript; Le Veillard, Louis Guillaume (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1790 June 23; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To William Temple Franklin, 1790 July 5; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Sarah Bache and Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 July 25; Orig. and typescript; Bache, William (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 July 28; Orig. and typescript; Bache, William (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 July 28; Orig. and typescript; Morris, Robert (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 Aug. 18; Orig. and typescript; Johonnot, Samuel Cooper (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 Sept. 1; Orig. and typescript; Vaughan, Benjamin (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 Sept. 3; Orig. and typescript; Vaughan, Benjamin (Reel 2)
  - Promissory note to William Temple Franklin, 1790 Sept. 30; Morris, Robert (Reel 2)
  - To Richard and Sarah Bache, 1790 Oct. 10; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 Oct. 16; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Sarah (Reel 2)
  - Power of attorney to George Fox, 1790 Oct. 30; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 2)
  - Memorandum and list of papers left with George Fox, 1790 Nov. 4; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 Nov. 5; Orig. and typescript; Johonnot, Samuel Cooper (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Apr. 20; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1791 Apr. 22; Orig. and typescript; Jefferson, Thomas. (Reel 2)
  - To Marianne Williams and the Somerset Folks, 1791 Apr. 25; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Apr. 29; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 May 9; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 June 5; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 June 15-22; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Adam Kuhn, 1791 June 19; Markoe, Margaret Hartman (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 June 27; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 July 1; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Aug. 17; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Aug. 23; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Aug. 27; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Aug. 29; Orig. and typescript; Markoe, Peter, 1752?-1792 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1791 Sept. 1; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Sept. 8; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Sept. 15; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Sept. 19; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1791 Sept. 20; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Sept. 23; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Bache, 1791 Sept. 23; Orig. and typescript; Kuhn, Adam (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Oct. 3; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Oct. 4; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Margaret Hartman Markoe, 1791 Oct. 4; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1791 Oct. 10; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Elizabeth Markoe, 1791 Dec.; ADf and typescript; Bache, Margaret Hartman (Reel 2)
  - To Isaac Hartman, 1792 Mar. 21; ADf and typescript; Bache, Margaret Hartman (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 May 18; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 June 7; Markoe, Peter, 1752?-1792 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 June 12; Markoe, Margaret Hartman (Reel 2)
    Also includes Francis Markoe to Benjamin Franklin Bache
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 June 13; Markoe, Francis (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 June 28; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 July 2; Library Company of Philadelphia. (Reel 2)
  - To Peter Markoe, 1792 July 6; Cy; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To unidentified recipient, 1792 July 8; Cy; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 July 18; Markoe, Peter, 1752?-1792 (Reel 2)
  - To the Administrators of the estate of Isaac Hartman, 1792 July 21; Cy; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 July 23; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 July 23; Markoe, Peter, 1752?-1792 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Aug. 1; Markoe, Francis (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Aug. 17; Markoe, Peter, 1752?-1792 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Aug. 19; Markoe, Francis (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Sept. 3; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Sarah (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Sept. 3; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Sarah (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Sept. 4; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Sarah (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Sept. 10; Markoe, Peter, 1752?-1792 (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Sept. 12; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Sarah (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Sept. 15; Markoe, William (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Nov. 5; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Nov. 5; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Nov. 6; Orig. and typescript; Morris, Robert (Reel 2)
  - To Sarah Bache, 1792 Nov. 25; Cy and transcript; Hamilton, A[bigail?] (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1792 Dec. 3; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Jan. 6; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Jan. 8; Markoe, William (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Jan. 9; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Jan. 9; Typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1793 Jan. 10; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1793 Jan. 10; Typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1793 Feb. 3; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To Richard Bache, 1793 Feb. 3; Typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 2)
  - To My Dear Children, 1793 Feb. 5; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Sarah (Reel 2)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Feb. 6; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Feb. 6; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Feb. 7; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Feb. 19; Orig. and typescript; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 3)
  - Orig. and typescript, 1790 Feb. 19; Typescript; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 Feb. 24; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 March 13; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1790 March 13; Typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Peter Markoe, 1793 Mar. 20-May 4; Cy; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
    Also includes Benjamin Franklin Bache to William Markoe
  - To William Markoe, 1793 Mar. 26; Cy; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 March; Fragment. Orig. and typescript; Bache, Sarah (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Apr. 5; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 Apr. 10; Markoe, William (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 May 1; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1793 May 8; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 May 9; Markoe, William (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1793 July 22; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Richard (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1793 Aug. 22; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1793 Aug. 22; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Anthony Wayne, 1793 Sept. 25; Cy, typescript and Cy of enclosures; Franklin, William Temple (Reel 3)
  - To Peter and Francis Markoe, 1793 Sept. 28; Cy; Hope and Co. (Reel 3)
  - Passport for William Bache, 1794 May 31; United States (Reel 3)
    Signed Edward Randolph, Sec. of State
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1794 Aug. 1; Orig. and typescript; Cramer, Louis Gabriel (Reel 3)
  - To Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1794 Aug. 1; Typescript; Cramer, Louis Gabriel (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1794 Sept. 27; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1794 Sept. 27; Typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To William Markoe, 1794 Oct. 4; Cy; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1794 Oct.?; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1794 (Tues.); Typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1794 (Fri.); Typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1794?; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To William Bache, 1795 Feb. 26; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To John Wolcot, 1795 Feb. 26; Cy; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)
  - To Richard Bache, 1795 Mar. 30; Orig. and typescript; Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 (Reel 3)